and people in Belgorod support the war
а люди в Белгороде поддерживают войну
against Ukraine or not - they don’t support it
против Украины или нет - не поддерживают
at all, no one actually supports it
вообще никто не поддерживает на самом-то
Well, because it wouldn’t be interesting to
деле Ну потому что не интересно бы по
fly to them and say Yes, I don’t know
ним прилетает да сказать Да я не знаю на
actually, it’s as if everyone doesn’t
самом деле как будто бы все не
support this situation, but how  I read
поддерживают эту ситуацию но как я читаю
Ukrainian public pages I did
украинские паблики у меня мне было всё
n’t care, I’m always not angry at Ukrainians Well,
равно всегда на украинцев я не зла Ну
I would have a neutral attitude in general
как бы мне вообще нейтрально
Hello Hello 18 years old there is there is a
Здравствуйте 18 лет есть есть есть
city Khmelnitsky from
города Хмельницкий откуда из
Russia what that I’m from the city Khmelnitsky Are
России что что я из города Хмельницкий А
you from Russia from Belgorod Well
вы из России откуда из Белгорода Ну
seriously  yes, these were real arrivals
серьёзно да а это реально были прилёты
Before the New Year,
Перед Новым годом
tight tights
жёсткие триго
Yes, it’s cool
Да прикольно
they fired at SMA Yes, and I can’t understand why
обстреливали Да и не могу понять почему
Putin seemed to undertake to defend Donbass yes And
Путин вроде взялся защищать Донбасс да А
here in just one day in Belgorod
тут только за один день в Белгороде
more people died than in 2 years there before
погибло больше чем за 2 года там перед
the war in Donbass Why can’t it
войной на Донбассе Почему не может
protect
защитить
Belgorod a few died very
Белгород погибло немного погибло очень
few died so 24 in just one day there
мало так 24 только за один день
were 100 casualties died and they died so
пострадавших было 100 погибло а поги так
look in the 2nd year on the entire Donbass and
смотрите в 2м году на всм Донбассе да и
on the occupied Ukrainian Russian side
с украинской российс стороны
Yes, 20 people died, of which 20 people died
оккупированной Да погибло 20 человек из
from the fighting 10 the rest are
них от боевых действий 10 остальные
somewhere there  mines were blown up there, yes,
где-то там на минах там подрывали да то
that is, 10 people died from shelling for the
есть 10 человек от обстрелов погибло за
whole year, yes And here in just one day in
весь год да А тут только за один день в
Belgorod
Белгороде
24 but we had frequent arrivals but
24 но у нас же были частые прилёты но у
we had arrivals not well, which were shot
нас были прилёты не ну которые сбивали
down by air defense because I have a
короче ПВО потому что у меня терраса
glass terrace Well there  it’s panoramic and you can see how
стеклянная Ну там панорамна и видно как
everything is flying. And that day I sat for
летит всё И вот в тот день я сидела часа
two hours, it was
два было
[ __ ] flying. In short, they flew air defense
бля полетели Короче они ПВО полетело
first before the missiles and then I already
сначала первее чем ракеты и потом уже
heard booms, such a shock wave. I
слышу бахи такая волна Ударная Я около
live near the center almost, and it turns out like
центра живу почти вот и получается вот
this, I don’t know. I’m sorry.  most likely there are
так вот я не знаю Мне жалко скорее всего
more children from there And in general it doesn’t
больше детей оттуда А так вообще всё
matter to all their showdowns about the war on the
равно на эту на все их разборки на войну
twenty-third I woke up in tears on the
двадцать третьего проснулась слезах
twenty-fourth and that’s all After that
двадцать четвёртого и всё После этого
I didn’t care anymore, I just
мне стало уже всё равно не я просто не
can’t understand why Putin can’t
могу понять почему Путин не может
protect the residents of Belgorod so that they don’t
защитить жителей Белгорода чтобы их не
get shelled  who knows, over there on oh
обстреливали кто его знает там вон на ой
on this one on Red Square, throw a
на этот на Красную Площадь бычком кинь
bull there already, the air defense will fly and no one cares about us. Well, yes, the most interesting thing that happens is that it turns out that Moscow made this war, defended itself, and Belgorod already you even know what the most
Белгород уже даже знаешь что самое
interesting thing is  already for everyone in Belgorod, even In
интересное уже всем на Белгород даже
short, everyone celebrated their own holidays Celebrated the
Короче все себе праздники Праздновали
New Year, in short, no one declared mourning,
Новый год короче никто траур не объявил
they announced
объявили у нас объявили
mourning in
траур в самом
Belgorod itself, in Rostov they announced, well, such
бел в Ростове объявили ну такие
suburban Rostov
пригородные Ростов
Kursk, I don’t remember something else, but we
Курск что-то ещё не помню но траур у нас
had some kind of mourning, well, Putin  I didn’t say there,
был какое-то ну там Путин не сказал там
this year was difficult for us. I did
этот год для нас был сложным Я даже его
n’t even listen to him. He didn’t even say anything about
не слушала он не сказал даже про
Belgorod. I
Белгород
still felt like they were shelling me. Yes,
с уже всё равно мне стало обстреляли Да
of course I cried, there were children on video
поплакала конечно там дети на видосах
screaming moms moms Help me, that’s it, that
орали мам мам Помоги мне вот это да это
was scary.
было страшно
Well, why?  residents of Belgorod, these
А ну почему жители Белгорода вот эти
mothers, don’t come out to the square there with a
мамы Да не выйдут там на площадь с
rally saying that Putin Protect
митингом что Путин Защити
Belgorod, yes, they will be packed up and taken away.
Белгород Да их упакуют и увезут Ну как
Well, they’ll kill them, so they’ll fly in and that’s
так а так их убьют так прилетит и
it, that is, they will be silent. Yes,
это ну то есть с они молчать будут Да
just like that, missiles will fly in and
так просто ракеты будут прилетать и
kill them in  Belgorod And so they are afraid
убивать их в Белгороде А так они боятся
that they will be taken to the police. Well, how
что их в милицию заберут Ну это как
funny they will pack them up,
смешно их их упакуют
even of
даже
course they will pack them up and take them away from this
де конечно их упакуют и заберут с этой
square,
площади
so that is, it turns out easier to sit
так так то есть получается проще сидеть
and wait until the rocket arrives. Why did
и ждать пока прилетит ракета Да по что
n’t Putin even know about this no now
Путин даже не узнал об этом нет сейчас
many are now leaving. That is, they are simply
многие сейчас уезжают А то есть просто
leaving, leaving their houses, not leaving their houses. Yes,
уезжают уезжают из домов не выходят Да
here we have delivery to Belgorod.
тут у нас доставка пому Белгороду возят
Well, I don’t know, now there is a square there,
Ну не знаю сейчас там площадь всегда у
we always had fireworks there on January 1st. Everything
нас салюты были там на 1 января Всё у
we had was a Christmas tree. We had a fire in the skating rink
нас было Ёлка У нас вот э горела в каток
that hit  in nono they drop a photo of not a
который попал в ноно скидывают фотку ни
single person on the mountain, the skating rink was burning in the
одного человека на горе каток горел в
very center, near the Christmas tree, and
самом в центре у нас возле ёлки да там
everyone was running there. Yes, but what got there, what
все бегали Да а что это туда попало что
flew there, I don’t know this one now this one oh oh
прилетело я не знаю этот сейчас этот о о
like oh what’s it called Oh
вроде бы о как она называется О
who are shooting at us  o o
которые обстреливают нас о о
Al Al Yes, here Al Yes, the alder flew
Аль Аль Да вот Аль Да ольха прилетела
there, that’s how I understood it, but I don’t know, I
туда вот как я поняла но я не знаю я
read everything from the news, I didn’t even
читаю то всё с новостей я туда даже не
go there. I’m afraid to go there at all, I
ездила Я туда вообще Боюсь ездить я туда
don’t touch there, and they’re preparing for elections there
не прикасаюсь а к выборам там готовятся
in
в
Belgorod. No, there will be elections there.  Yes, in
Белгороде Нет там выборы будут у вас да
the spring there will be a sunrise, everyone will go to
весной будут ВС рано все пойдут
vote,
голосовать
I don’t know. I don’t give a damn, honestly.
я не знаю Мне вообще по барабану честно
Let them vote for whoever they want. I’m
Пусть голосуют за кого хотят мне ты
not interested in politics. Yes, you know, it’s funny,
политикой не интересуешься да А знаешь в
look at the World Cup. Well, the fact is that
ЧМ прикол смотри Ну вот Дело в том что
missiles even fly into the houses of
ракеты оказывается прилетают даже в дома
those who are politicians.  not
тех кто политиками не
interested Yes, it’s
интересуется Да так это
true, yes it’s true, civilians.
правда да это правда мирных жителей
I just remember I was in the hospital back in
Просто я помн я лежала в больнице ещ Это
the year. I was put
был Т год меня положили сра вле
in the same place. Then a quadcopter fell on a residential building and a quadcopter flew into some apartment. And then I was sitting in the hospital and they
залетел А я тогда сидела в больнице и
told us  in my room there was a girl
нам сказали у меня в палате была девушка
with a child, it turns out she got up, moved away
с ребёнком она получается встала отошла
from the window, took the child, I immediately got up,
от окна взяла ребёнка я сразу же Встала
she will be with me Sonya, wake up, I get up,
она мене будет Сонь просыпайся я встаю
she says Sonya, Sonya, we are being bombed, I
Она говорит Сонь Сонь у нас бомбят я
see our missiles are flying like this,
смотрю у нас ракеты вот так летят вот
these fiery heats are coming to us
эти вот огненные жары заходит к нам
nurse I say Well, let's
медсестра Я говорю Ну давайте там в
go out into the corridor there She says you're
коридор выйдем Она говорит Вы что всё
sleeping fine and we see smoke just
нормально спите и мы видим дым просто
coming towards us I think, well, super we were told
идёт на нас думаю ну супер нам сказали
sleep it's all fine It's normal to
спите это всё нормально Это нормально
get used to it I say you're used to it Yes And how
привыкнуть Я говорю вы привыкли да А как
and people in Belgorod support the war
а люди в Белгороде поддерживают войну
against  Ukraine or not They don’t support it
против Украины или нет У не поддерживают
at all Nobody actually supports it Well
вообще никто не поддерживает на самом-то
Because it would be interesting to fly in on them
деле Ну Потому что интересно бы по ним
Yes skaz Yes I don’t know in
прилетает Да сказа Да я не знаю на самом
fact it’s as if everyone doesn’t support
деле как будто бы все не поддерживают
this situation but how I read Ukrainian
эту ситуацию но как я читаю украинские
public pages I had  anyway,
паблики у меня мне было всё равно всегда
I’m not always angry with Ukrainians. Well, I’m not
на украинцев я не зла Ну как бы не
generally neutral, as if I
вообще нейтрально отношусь как бы у меня
have friends here in Belgorod from
и друзья есть которые тут в Белгороде с
Ukraine who moved a long time
Украины которые переехали ещё
ago, as if I’m neutral
давным-давно как бы я нейтрально
about this, but I go to the
отношусь к этому но я захожу в
Ukrainian public and they post it there  about the
Украинский паблик и там выкладывают о
arrival in Belgorod like catch,
прилёт по Белгороду типа ловите
everyone come up to the windows, put your
подходите все к окнам подставляйте свои
eyes and your faces there in the Kharkov
глазки и свои лица там в Харьковской
group Yes, and here are the comments for
групе Да и комментарии вот
you I think Well, here they are Why do you
вам Я думаю А ну вот такие А зачем Вы
go to Ukrainian public pages If you are
заходите в украинские паблик Если вы же
not interested in politics, why do you
не интересуетесь политикой зачем вы
think Ukrainian I come  When
считаете украинский я захожу Когда
you know they write that there
знаешь там пишут то что там на Белгород
will now be arrivals to Belgorod and there in Kharkov
будут сейчас прилёты и там в Харькове
When we have arrivals I go there
Когда у нас идут прилёты я захожу там
how many more arrivals will there be there they write there
сколько ещё прилётов будет там пишут там
three arrivals I’m sitting there there
три прилёта Я там сижу вке там три
will be three arrivals and that’s it I’m leaving it turns out it’s true
прилёта будет и всё я выхожу это правда
But according to  that is, a Tarkovite
оказывается А по то есть тарковчанин
yes yes So they actually write there And I really
да да Так там же реально пишут А реально
understood it’s cool, that is, and semi That is, I
понял прикольно то есть и полу То есть я
understand correctly that Kharkov
правильно понимаю что Харьковские
publics force these arrivals to make
паблики заставляю эти прилёты заставляют
you interested in politics You go
вас интересоваться политикой Вы заходите
to Ukrainian chats to see the news Well,
в украинские чаты посмотреть новости Ну
when one arrives there, I’ll go and see
когда там прилетит одна я зайду посмотрю
how many there are  missiles Yes, roughly speaking, that’s
сколько там ракет Да грубо говоря та а
what, why do you think people in
как Как вы думаете почему люди вот в
Kharkov public pages say that,
Харьковских пабликах так говорят вот там
keep your eyes open there And so on, why
держите там глазки И так дальше почему
Well, because we’re shooting at them,
Ну потому что мы по ним стреляем
oh So, what about you,
о Так а что же вас
so to me, I don’t give a damn,
так мне то что мне по барабану мне
honestly, to me  Armed Forces anyway, let them shoot. Let them
честно мне ВС равно пусть стреляют Пусть
shoot at us. I don’t care. I’ll soon
нас стреляют мне уже всё равно я скоро
move from here to another country. Yes, I’m
перееду отсюда в другую страну
planning to go to Japan for a long time.
мне да планирую далеко надолго в Японию
But
Но это
you’ll be working for a long time.
ещё долго м
It’s very embarrassing at the
работаете Это очень стыдно на пункте
xmail delivery point, but was it something from an
выдачи xmail а а что это было что-то из
advertisement? No, no  It’s not just a
рекламы Да нене не просто это пункт
pick-up point where everyone treats him badly,
выдачи который все плохо к нему
in short, it’s the worst
относятся короче это самый ужасный пункт
pick-up point. Well, 25,000 a month, the salary is
выдачи Ну 25.000 в месяц зарплата
of course the worst, I put up with these money there.
конечно самый ужасный я там терплю этих
Invasions 25,000 - That’s 250
Нашествия 25.000 - Это 250
dollars No The dollar has fallen, how much is it
долларов Нет Доллар же упал он сколько
now, roughly speaking,
сейчас грубо говоря
a hundred then yes 250 250  dollars
сотня то да 250 250 долларов
Yes, that’s how we live And how old are you?
Да вот так и живём А сколько тебе
19 this year
лет 19 в этом году
Ponya Well, yes, 250 dollars for Belgorod
Поня Ну да 250 долларов для Белгорода
is such a salary. Well, here we have
это такая себе зарплата Ну у нас
40. This seems to be the average salary from
40 Это вроде бы средняя зарплата от
[music]
[музыка]
every day billions of dollars, like
каждый день миллиарды долларов типа
millions of dollars
миллионы долларов по Украине
are shooting out across Ukraine, yes  that is, ca
выстреливает да то есть Неужели эти
n’t this money be used to develop the
деньги нельзя пустить на там развитие
infrastructure economy there so that you
экономики инфраструктуры чтобы у вас
have good jobs and so on, who
работы были хорошие и так дальше кто его
knows what’s in his head I don’t know what’s in his
знает что в башке Я не знаю к нему в
head, well, all the people
голову получается ну всему народу
understand that their money is going somewhere
понимают что ихние бабки уходят куда-то
to nowhere Yes, theirs  Moreover, they are also
в никуда Да их при том ещё и
shelling And so on Well,
обстреливают И так дальше Ну
just Well, we’re sitting waiting as he
просто Ну сидим ждм как он
speaks, in 3 days he went as far as Kiev, before
говори за 3 дня зашёл до ки до Киева до
this he didn’t go to Kiev, he didn’t come to Kiev where did he come from,
этой не до Киева он в Киев не зашёл
in short, there
откуда он дош короче там сило в Киеве
was some kind of power in Kiev, see The question is this  you
какое-то было смотри Вопрос такой у вас
are in Belgorod, I saw that there were
в Белгороде есть я вот смотрел что были
arrivals in the area of
прилёты в район
kreida kreida yes It’s almost near the center
крейда крейда да Это около центра почти
And what does
А что означает
kreida mean I mean, just, well, kreida, well,
крейда В смысле Просто ну крейда ну а
what do they mine
что там добывают
there? There seems to be an oil depot
там это там нефтебаза вроде бы рядом
nearby, yes yes Well, there are quarries in the
была да да Ну что там карьеры что в
area  kreida, what
районе крейда что
they mine I don’t
добывают Я не
know, well, there’s chalk there, and sometimes there’s limestone
знаю ну там мел да бывает известняк
Yes, honestly, I don’t know, I’ve been to the crete
Да я честно я не знаю я на крете один
once in my life.
раз в жизни
In the Ukrainian language, kreida is chalk,
была в украинском языке крейда это мел
just like in German. It seems like it’s a
также как и из немецкого Вроде это пошло
chalky mountain. It seems
меловая гора Вроде бы
so. Why is it in your area?  it's called
да А почему у вас район называется
kreida and not chalk
крейда а не мел
What What Why is this area where the
Чего Чего Почему вот этот район где
chalk mountain is called kreida and not
меловая гора называется крейда а не
lovita well because like this because
ловита ну потому что как этот потому что
we were Ukraine in kaki In what year
мы были Украиной в каки В каком Като
was Kato there I don't remember which year honestly but I
годе там Я не помню в каком честно но
remember
помню
1919 Yes yes yes that's right super  super,
1919 Да да да правильно супер супер а
but there is a mood among you people
как вот у вас среди людей есть
that maybe it would be better to
настроение что может лучше было
return to
вернуться в
Ukraine Yes, no one is thinking about that. Well,
Украину Да не об этом никто не думает Ну
you will be in Ukraine and Ukraine will not
ите будете в Украине и Украина вас не
fire at you, yes, I don’t know, in fact,
обстреливать да я не знаю на самом деле
I thought about this a long time ago
я думала насчёт этого давным-давно ещё
but despite the fact that Donbass, God forbid, and everyone
но смотря на то как Упаси Донбасс и все
says that it’s
говорят что это
looting, we are now Belgorod looting, like, he
лупасит мы сейчас Белгород лупасит типа
separated from us in 1990 and
э отсоединился от нас в 1990 году да и
went to a unit in the Russian Federation
перешёл в часть в Российскую Федерацию
Yes, to the FSR in the Russian Federation We
Да в ФСР по Российскую Федерацию Мы
want to return Belgorod back That is,
хотим вернуть Белгород назад То есть
if they hold  referendum on
если в Белгороде проведут референдум о
accession in Ukraine and Ukraine then
присоединении в Украине и Украина тогда
undertakes not to shell Belgorod, what
обязуется не обстреливать Белгород как
do you think people
думаете люди
will vote
проголосуют
M no 100% no, that is, you choose to be
М нет 100% нет то есть вы выберете чтобы
bombed like But don’t join
вас бомбили типа Но не присоединитесь к
Ukraine I’m not talking about myself, I’m talking
Украине Я говорю не про себя я говорю
about people because looking at these
про людей потому что смотря на вот этих
grandmothers  who have been voting for Putin for
бабушек которые голосуют за Путина уже
how many years they will vote for him
сколько лет они будут про него за него
and will always be in their place
голосовать и будут всегда на их месте Ну
Well, well, not grandmothers but young people,
хорошо а не бабушки а молодёжь молодёжь
for example, it turns out that they would vote
например получается что проголосовала бы
for joining Ukraine and the youth I think
за присоединение к Украине да молодёжь
yes I think yes I don’t know for sure Well, as I think
да Думаю да точно не знаю Ну как я думаю
as I think Well, in principle, yes, because
как я считаю Ну в принципе да потому что
what is Russia for you, Russia is you for Russia,
что для вас Россия Россия вы для России
you are some kind of periphery Yes, she still
вы Периферия какая-то Да она всё равно
doesn’t consider you normal Russians Yes,
вас не считает русскими нормальными Да
that’s why she’s hammering on why we do
вот поэтому и забивает на почему у нас
n’t know why there is
не знаю почему со стороны украинцев на
such aggression on us from the Ukrainians  look,
нас агрессия такая во смотрите потому
because many of us think that you are
что у нас многие Да думают что вы в
Russian in Belgorod, and that’s why you are
Белгороде русские Да и поэтому вы нас
shelling us. We also tell many
обстреле Мы тоже рассказываем многим
people that look, Belgrade is our
людям что смотрите Белград - это наши
Ukrainians who have been under
украинцы которые с 1919 года находятся в
Russian occupation since 1919, you understand, and we
оккупации Российской понимаете и мы
must liberate Belgrade, liberate
должны освободить Белград освободить
Belgrade, yes this is  I know, well, no, it’s just
Белград Да это я знаю Ну нет просто
aggression on the part of people, as if I
агрессия стороны людей как будто бы я в
launched these missiles at them there and I’m
них там ракеты эти запустила и я их там
not there, I mean, I’m not doing this, they look,
нет я что я этим не занимаюсь они смотри
they don’t know, they don’t know, they think
они не знают они не знают они думают
maybe because of Putin, maybe some
может из-за Путина может какая-то
kind of Putinka  Russian yes But if I
путинка типа русская да Но если вот я
say So when Belgorod is liberated
скажу Так что когда Белгород освободят
Yes when all these troops are driven out of
Да когда эти все войска выбьют из
Belgorod and then they will hold a referendum
Белгорода да тогда проведут референдум
Yes well, that is, we will not annex
Да ну то есть мы не будем присоединять
Belgorod to Ukraine We have Ukrainian
Белгород к Украине У нас вот украинская
politics Yes, so that new regions will be
политика Да чтобы новые регионы они
included only for this reason  results of
входили только по этому по результатам
the referendum and we will hold a referendum in Belgorod
референдума и мы проведём в Белгороде
yes Therefore, if 50
референдум да Поэтому если 50
percent plus one vote votes for
процентом плюс оди Голос проголосует за
joining Ukraine Yes, we will take Well,
присоединение к Украине Да мы возьмём Ну
with our Western partners,
с нашими западными партнёрами
Belgorod Belgorod first in the form of the
Белгородский белгородско сначала в виде
Belgorod People's Republic in the
Белгородской народной Республики в
transition period of 8 years Yes, and then
переходной период 8 лет Да а потом
we will include it in
включим в состав уже
Ukraine  bnr Yes, first there will be bnr 8 years
Украины бнр Да сначала будет бнр 8 лет
bnr Yes, a transition period like in order
бнр Да переходной период типа для того
to adapt your legislation
чтобы адаптировать ваше законодательство
to our standards to the standards of
к нашему стандарты к стандартам
the European Union Yes, and then you will become part of
Евросоюза Да а потом войдёте в состав
Ukraine, I
Украины
don’t know Well, I don’t support this at all, I
не знаю Ну я вообще это никак не
don’t support anyone at all,
поддерживаю вообще никого не поддерживаю
I honestly don’t care about me, uh, everyone  the
мне честно безразлично меня э вся
situation, that is, what will happen, for example, that
ситуация то есть что будет например что
in Belgorod there will be Russia, that Ukraine,
в в Белгороде будет Россия что Украина
that NATO, that America, it doesn’t matter,
что НАТО что Америка всё равно Да пофиг
yes, the main thing is that I’m alive, great, I
да Главное чтобы я жива была Здорово
understand, okay, you have a question for me,
понял хорошо у вас ко мне есть какой-то
no, everything is fine, I understand, okay,
вопрос нет всё хорошо понял хорошо
let’s
давайте
subscribe to my Telegram  right now
подпишись на мий Telegram прямо зараз
ovin and Pok
овин а Пок
more and more respectfully YouTube Zaga us
дуже и дуже важливо YouTube Зага нас
through srg org in new ban and even more
через срг ор в ньй бан и дуже багато
richly video I don’t show people immediately I don’t show
вдео не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information about streams For this purpose,
информация про стрими Тому для того щоб
we need Mali to write an operational link
ми Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
directly at once and while there in telegram okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телеграми окм
video more  tezh tsikava and korisna information
видео ще теж цикава и корисна информация
and we will call you trima postiyny
и мы пон з вами трима постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write M
пиши M